Guide to the Emmanuel Montoya collection of Chicano publications M1804
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Emmanuel Montoya collection of Chicano publications
1969-1993
M1804
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
1.0 Linear feet (one manuscript box, one flat box)
Chicano/Latino publications including magazines and exhibition catalogs.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in 2010 and 2012.
Scope and Contents
Emmanuel Montoya assembled this collection of Chicano publications, primarily concerning San Francisco Bay Area artists (including muralists), writers, musicians, political activists, etc. Included are artists' exhibition catalogs, and the anniversary issue of LOW RIDER ("projecting the positive image of Low Riding Culture"). Also of note are six issues of UNIVERSAL, a multicultural community service publication from Redwood City, California, 1975-1976.
Related Archival Materials note
Related collection: M1930 Emmanuel Montoya collection of Chicano publications, 1976-1997.
Montoya, Emmanuel C. (Emmanuel Catarino); Exhibitions --Catalogs.; Mexican American art--California.; Mexican Americans--California--Periodicals.
- Victoria Alba: Artists with a Mission, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Juana Alicia: Savados Hispanos (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Artistas Mexico Americanos de San Francisco, CA - exhibit catalog, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- El Barrio, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Caracol, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Chicanos..., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Chisme Arte, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Chispas, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cipactli, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Con Safos, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lo del Corozon: Heartbeat of a Culture - exhibit catalog, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- La Cucaracha, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Tim Drescher: San Francisco murals - checklist 1914-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Garcia Rupert: Pastel Drawings - exhibit catalog, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Carmen Lomas Garzaa - exhibit catalog, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Low Rider, circa 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Norte, circa 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- El Pocho Che, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- El Pocho Che, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Recent Raza Murals in Radical America, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Tin-Tan, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Universal, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)